<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OpenELA</title><link>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/</link><description>Recent content on OpenELA</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/about/</guid><description>OpenELA is a trade association of open source Enterprise Linux distribution developers founded in support of the spirit of open source to create continuity for all Enterprise Linux downstream distributions. Our mission is to provide a secure, transparent, and reliable Enterprise Linux source that is globally available to all as a buildable base.
The long term success of our mission is ensured through the formation of this foundation with complete commitment to non-partisanship, transparency, community, inclusivity, and public benefit.</description></item><item><title>CIQ, Oracle and SUSE Create Open Enterprise Linux Association for a Collaborative and Open Future</title><link>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/news/hello_world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/news/hello_world/</guid><description>New trade association brings together open source Enterprise Linux community It will provide an open process to access source code that organizations can use to build distributions compatible with RHEL RENO, Nev., AUSTIN, Texas, and LUXEMBOURG—August 10, 2023—CIQ, Oracle and SUSE today announced their intent to form the Open Enterprise Linux Association (OpenELA), a collaborative trade association to encourage the development of distributions compatible with Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) by providing open and free Enterprise Linux (EL) source code.</description></item><item><title>Join</title><link>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/join/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/join/</guid><description>Absolutely everyone is welcome to join!
From Enterprise Linux downstream derivatives, to organizations that depend on Enterprise Linux, to vendors, and individuals who just love being part of something amazing, YOU ARE INVITED!
How to Join: We are still in the early makings of the project, so the first step in becoming part of what we are doing is to join us and say hello!
Join the OpenELA Team on Slack note: Slack invite links sometimes need to be regenerated.</description></item><item><title>OpenELA Announcements</title><link>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/announcements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/announcements/</guid><description> OpenELA Announces kernel-lts Project in Support of Linux Kernel 4.14 (March 12th, 2024) OpenELA Initiates a Documentation Repository for the Community (December 13th, 2023) OpenELA Marks Major Milestones in Governance and Code Availability (November 2nd, 2023) OpenELA Current Status and What&amp;rsquo;s Coming Next (September 6th, 2023) CIQ, Oracle and SUSE Create Open Enterprise Linux Association for a Collaborative and Open Future (August 10th, 2023)</description></item><item><title>OpenELA Announces kernel-lts Project in Support of Linux Kernel 4.14</title><link>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/news/2024.03.12-support-linux-kernel-4.14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/news/2024.03.12-support-linux-kernel-4.14/</guid><description>Author: OpenELA Community Date: March 12th, 2024
As support from the larger open source community concludes, enterprise vendors team up to collaborate on long-term kernel maintenance
RENO, Nev., AUSTIN, Texas, and LUXEMBOURG—March 12, 2024— OpenELA is committing to providing a platform for developers to collaborate on the maintenance of the 4.14 Linux kernel after community support ended in January.
The OpenELA kernel-lts project is a repository that contains a continuation of long-term maintenance kernel releases hosted on kernel.</description></item><item><title>OpenELA Current Status and What's Coming Next</title><link>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/news/2023.09.07-current_status/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/news/2023.09.07-current_status/</guid><description>Author: Alan Clark (CTO Office, SUSE) Date: September 7th, 2023
TL;DR
OpenELA is still developing and moving quickly We are working on technical organization, documentation, tooling, and automation Come and join us! On August 10th, CIQ, Oracle and SUSE announced their intent to launch the Open Enterprise Linux Association (OpenELA). That announcement contained several key goals, mission statements and operating principles the effort will be based upon to best achieve those goals.</description></item><item><title>OpenELA Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/faq/</guid><description>What is OpenELA? It is a non-profit trade association of open source Enterprise Linux distribution developers founded in support of the spirit of open source to create continuity for all Enterprise Linux downstream distributions.
What is Enterprise Linux? There are many Linux Distributions that are perfectly suitable for enterprise use cases and environments. For the purpose of this charter and project, OpenELA recognizes “Enterprise Linux” (EL) as 1:1 and bug-for-bug source code compatibility which today is aligned to RHEL and CentOS.</description></item><item><title>OpenELA Initiates a Documentation Repository for the Community</title><link>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/news/2023.12.13-initiate-documentation-repository/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/news/2023.12.13-initiate-documentation-repository/</guid><description>Author: Antoinette O’Sullivan (senior director of documentation for Linux, virtualization, and systems, Oracle) Date: December 13, 2023
OpenELA is pleased to announce the creation of a user documentation repository OpenELA invites further documentation contributions from the community User Documentation Repository Now Available OpenELA is pleased to announce the creation of a user documentation repository. From this starting point, contributors are now able to add documentation as they work through the source code repositories and make relevant notes.</description></item><item><title>OpenELA Marks Major Milestones in Governance and Code Availability</title><link>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/news/2023.11.02-governance_and_code_availability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://openela.github.io/openela.org/pr-preview/pr-31/news/2023.11.02-governance_and_code_availability/</guid><description>Author: OpenELA Community Date: November 2nd, 2023
Source code for packages is now available (and more is on the way) Incorporation is complete, and the Technical Steering Committee has been formed to guarantee access to Enterprise Linux packages RENO, Nev., AUSTIN, Texas, and LUXEMBOURG—November 2, 2023—OpenELA today announced the public release of the Enterprise Linux source code along with important technical and governance milestones. OpenELA is a trade association of open source Enterprise Linux distribution developers originally founded by CIQ, Oracle and SUSE.</description></item></channel></rss>